# Koladele Olaitan

Front-end Developer & Technical Writer/Blogger

in LinkedIn

**%** +2347081540289

Portfolio

GitHub

Blog

# **About**

I'm a Front-end Developer with over 3 years of experience making the web better by deploying amazing web applications with a portfolio to show for it. I use my skills to build first-class, mobile-responsive, speed-optimized, and accessible websites. I love open-source!

## Technical Skills

- Markup: Semantic HTML, JSX.
- UI & Styling: CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Material Design, Figma, Adobe XD.
- No-code Tools: WordPress, Elementor, MailChimp.
- Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript.
- Libraries and Frameworks: React, Next.js, GSAP, Axios, Swiper.js, Leaflet.js, Chart.js.
- Bundlers & Linters: Webpack, Parcel, ESLint, Prettier.
- Hosting & OS: Netlify, Vercel, cPanel, Linux (preferred), MacOS, Windows.
- Additional: NPM, Technical documentation, REST APIs, Responsive Web Design, Speed Optimization, SEO.

# **Work Experience**

### Web Content Writer

#### Decentralize Africa

Feb 2022 - Present (8 months +)

- Wrote creative content that promote the brand.
- Improved SEO for higher page and post rankings on search engines.
- Did editing and proofreading of existing and new articles to ensure they are of good quality.
- Written over 25 articles so far.

## Frontend Developer

#### Unlimited.ng

Nov 2020 - July 2021 (9months)

- Taught 5 students HTML, CSS, and JavaScript at a bootcamp hosted by the company.
- Built a website for the bootcamp to automate the registration process and onboarding.
- Awarded as the most punctual employee.
- Collaborated with the marketing team to source for clients via various means and also discuss with clients to know their project requirements.
- Landed the company one paid client.
- Worked on over 15 unique projects in an 9-month period

## Soft Skills

- Collaborative
- Communicative
- Emotional Intelligence
- Friendly Personality
- Fast Learner
- Humble, Happy, and Hungry (for knowledge)
- Passion for learning and development
- Problem-Solving
- Self-starter
- Team Leadership

# **Achievements**

- I have written articles on WordPress and other tools I use in building websites.
- Over 20 merged pull requests in 10+ open-source repositories including Ubuntu and Signoz.
- I read about a problem in responsive website design and I built a tool that solves the problem.
- I organized a webinar where I taught 120 students about crypto and Blockchain. Here is a link to the resources (written guides and videos) I made for the webinar.

## Education

## Univeristy of Ilorin

Bachelor of Education - BEd, Counselor Education

2018 - 2022

- I held 3 different office posts in 3 years in a students' organization.
- I gave a talk on Blockchain at an FTX-organized event that saw over 50 students in attendance.
- Was awarded a Federal Government Scholarship.